Guide to the Dean of Faculty records, 1967-2007.
Dean of Faculty records,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dean of Faculty records, 1967-2007.
11-1-3282
Cornell University. Dean of Faculty.
1.4 cubic ft.
Minutes and reports.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes the minutes of the Faculty Senate meetings (1999-present), various reports concerning athletics, minority education, free speech, the Cranch report and other university issues.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Cornell University Senate was formed in 1970. Its predecessor, the Constituent Assembly, provided the preliminary organization. In 1977 the CU Senate was replaced by the Cornell Faculty Council of Representatives and in February 1996 this was replaced by the Faculty Senate.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes the minutes of the Faculty Senate meetings (1999-present), various reports concerning athletics, minority education, free speech, the Cranch report and other university issues.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University. Dean of Faculty.; Cranch, Edmund T.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University--Administration; Cornell University--Athletics.; Cornell University.Faculty Senate.
Subjects:
African Americans--Study and teaching.; Minorities--Education (Higher)--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Freedom of speech.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted to permission of the office of origin.
RELATED MATERIALS
Related collection: Cornell University Dean of Faculty Records, #11-1-1279
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Reports and memos
  - Committee on Academic Programs and Policies - 1973 Statement on the Center for Improvement of Undergraduate Education and Report, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Africana Studies Report, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - An Approach to Black Studies - by James Turner; Report on Wari House; Faculty Appointments for Afro-American Studies - from W. K. Kennedy, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Task Force on Athletics - 1999; CU NCAA Athletics Certification Self-Study - 1998, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cornell in the Seventies, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cornell in the Seventies - memos, correspondence, response, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cranch Report, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cranch Report - Responses from Committees, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cranch Committee- President's Committee on Long Range Financing for the University - 1972; FCR Response - 1973, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Activism - CU Administration's comments; demands of the Student Alliance Against Racism, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letter to Cornell re: demonstrations - 1985; various clippings, memos re: disruptions - 1965-1989, 1965-1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Tuition protest - 1974; Faculty Volunteers Ad Hoc Committee - 1969, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - City of Ithaca Disturbance - Ad Hoc Committee Report, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Carpenter Hall Sit-In, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - McKersie Speech, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Disruptions - Faculty Council and Faculty Minutes, 1951-1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Black Power", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Campus Unrest, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Report of the Committee on Academic Freedom and Tenure, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Disruptions, Divestment - Clippings, 1968-1985 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Disruptions, Divestments - Clippings, 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Hispanic Studies Protest and Demonstration, 1991 and 1993 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - History of the Financial Aid Policy Committee, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Free Speech - Committee material, memos, correspondence, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Free Speech - articles, correspondence, memos, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Free Speech- corresponedence, articles, papers, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Free Speech - correspondence, memos, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Free Speech- articles, correspondence, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Report (Kahn-Bowers) of the Faculty Committee on the Quality of Undergraduate Instruction, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Bailey Hall Disturbance - Ky Report, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Bailey Hall Disturbance - Ky Report, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Bailey Hall Disturbance - Ky Report, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Melby Report - To Advise on Ways of Increasing Outisde Research Support to the University, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Subcommittee on Minority Education, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minority Education Committee's Recommendations on Cohen/Gates Report, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Minority Education at Cornell - CAPP, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Minority Education Committee - summary, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Williams Commission, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Report of the Special Committee of the University Faculty on Education - Olaf Larson, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Task Force Committee - Long - Chairman, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Lab - (California), 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - McConnell Report on Fringe Benefits, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Campus Unrest - Robertson Report, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Commission on Interdependence of University Regulations, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Status of Research Personnel - Van Riper - Chair, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Ratner Report - Financial Status of the University, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Self-Governance Reports, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Report of South African Committee to FCR, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Provost's Task Force on the Future of the Social Sciences at Cornell - Commissioned by Don Randel and Ron Ehrenberg, January 8, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Series II. Faculty Senate
  - Faculty Senate, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Faculty Senate Minutes, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Faculty Senate Minutes, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Faculty Senate Minutes, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Faculty Senate Minutes, May 2001-November 2001 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Faculty Senate Minutes, February 2002-April 2002 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Faculty Senate Minutes, May 2002-October 2002 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Faculty Senate Minutes, November 2002-March 2003 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Faculty Senate Minutes, May 2003-September 2003 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Faculty Minutes, 2006 (Box 3)
  - Committee Nominations Packet, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Meeting Notice, 2006 (Box 3)
  - Stephen H. Weiss Presidential Fellows Committee, 2007 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Senate Minutes, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Senate Minutes, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Senate Minutes, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Senate Minutes, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Senate Minutes, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Faculty Senate Minutes and Mailings, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Faculty Senate Minutes, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Guidelines for Photocopying, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Governance Digest for Members of the Faculty Council of Representatives, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 10)